Gunawan Wijaya

Personal Information

Degree: BS in Computer Science

Nationality: Indonesian

DOB: 10 December 1991

Gender: Male

Mobile: +62 81703020777 Email: **gunawan@wijaya.cc**

Website: https://gunawan.wijaya.cc

Career Summary

8+ years of experience in Software Development and Engineering, from Travel & Booking Agent System, Internet of Things, API-centric apps. Focused on low CPU, low memory, & low latency web & mobile apps on slow internet networks to deliver good quality UI/UX to the user, to the latest complex system involving thousands of server instances.

Technical Expertise

Golang, JavaScript, Python, Rust, Redis, Java*, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Neo4J*, Cassandra, Aliyun*, AWS, Azure, GCP, Kubernetes

* means little experience through exposure in workplace, not a favorite though

Professional Experience

Koinworks, Jakarta, ID (https://koinworks.com)

Aug 2021 – Present

Engineering Manager - NEO Pod

- Manage 20+ peoples in cross functional team (Android, iOS, QA, FE, BE)
- Assisting stakeholders to create the next neo-bank experience to Koinworks users
- Build CI/CD pipeline to smoothly deliver features & releases to end-users
- Enforcing strict PR review & constant pair programming with BE
- Enforcing strong encryption on all personal identifiable information
- Encourage knowledge sharing session to build an open source mindset
- Guides and listen to team members to help them to own the product
- Guides teams to build Testing Framework to reduce regression on features delivery
- Automation to be a priority task for every team member in order to maintain quality
- Delegate most of technical tasks and maintain a clear view of management side

Tokopedia, Jakarta, ID (https://tokopedia.com)

Nov 2018 - Jul 2021

Sr. Software Engineer - Logistic Orchestra Squad (Mar 2020 - Present)

- Owning delivery module (base module of Orchestra)
- TDD first on each iteration
- Leverage Github Action as development pipeline
- Major refactoring on early stage to avoid a larger tech-debt
- Reconciliation to partner as a report system
- Handover package report system
- Tracking status using state-machine-like mapper function
- Multi segmentation delivery tracking by miles (Pickup, First, Middle, Last)
- Real-time monitoring (outstanding, potential late, overSLA, withinSLA)

Sr. Software Engineer - Logistic Rates Squad (Nov 2018 - Mar 2020)

- Working closely w/ Golang, Redis, NSQ, PostgreSQL on GitHub
- Ensuring the system to work seamlessly with 3rd party logistics API
- Writing documentation on each 3rd party rate requests
- Ensuring that unit test running properly on every changes
- Code refactoring for clarity & better development experience

Pomona, Jakarta, ID (https://pomona.id)

Sep 2017 - Oct 2018

Software Engineer

- Greedy algorithm on request processing on all available resource in parallel
- Provide robust API using SOA based on pure Python + Node.JS + GraphQL
- Fuzzy Search FMCG prediction on receipt text in each retailer
- Unit test implementation on Machine Learning Python API
- Seamless experience from Development to Production via makefile
- PostgreSQL using Sequelize & MongoDB using Mongoose

Maven Lab Pte. Ltd., SG (https://mavenlab.com)

Jan 2016 – Apr 2017

Analyst Programmer

- Plan and re-design medical inventory stock system for "Lexus" Duke-NUS Intranet.
- Perform business and technical analysis to upgrade the promotion system for Magento powered "PanMalayan" pharmaceutical e-commerce.
- Manage day-to-day development processes, including testing and implementation, and ensure quality and timely delivery.
- Projects
 - o "Lexus", Duke-NUS medical inventory stock logging system (Drupal, AJAX)
 - o "PanMalayan", pharmaceutical e-commerce (Magento, AJAX)
 - Prime Minister's Office Singapore Landing page, blog, update and various information on <u>pmo.gov.sg</u> focus on design implementation (Drupal, AJAX)
 - Prime Minister's Office Singapore National Climate Change Secretariat <u>nccs.gov.sg/competition/nccc2016</u> design implementation (Drupal, AJAX)
 - Prime Minister's Office Singapore Corrupt Practices Investigation Bureau cpib.gov.sg analyze and bug fix (Drupal, AJAX)

Vi8e Interactive Pte. Ltd., SG (https://vi8e.com)

Sep 2015 - Dec 2015

Front End Developer

- Develop theme and plugin based on WordPress from designer to used in CMS.
- Research and Development on new themes to be used in Yii based e-commerce platform in Giant Singapore.
- Projects
 - Online Registration Form for International Conference on Court Excellence, (WordPress, Yii, AJAX)
 - Giant Online Singapore e-commerce beta theme research and development (AngularJS, Yii, AJAX)

PT. Omnia Media, Bali, ID

May 2014 - Jan 2015

Web Developer

- Manage day-to-day development processes, including testing and implementation, and ensure quality and timely delivery.
- Developed themes and plugins for WordPress based website to be used in CMS as client requested, from collecting user's feedback to promotion system
- Projects
 - Design Implementation from scratch to live site for internal projects such as Spotbyte SEO specialist, Omniascribes content editor, Barefoot web development, Ubudio recording studio, and WeDoAmazingVideos animation studio. That time, Omnia Media was known as the best company with a digital environment in Ubud, Bali. (WordPress, Bootstrap, AJAX)
 - Work in a team for client projects from Massimo Italian restaurant, dentist app for United States owned ToonDentistry, Australian owned villa booking system for Purimas Lombok, and product promotion for Buddyguard Thailand. (WordPress, Bootstrap, AJAX)

PT. Agung Greenland Property, Bali, ID

Nov 2013 - May 2014

Lead Web Developer

- Manage day-to-day development processes, including testing and implementation, and ensure quality to convert user into customer.
- Managing Blog, Forum, and Gallery to be responsive and fast for users.
- Developed spam killer script in forum. Reducing from thousands of spam per month.
- Projects
 - Research and Development, testing and implementation from scratch to live site that consists of blog, forum, and gallery (PHP, Bootstrap, AJAX)

Non-Professional Experience

Private Project Jan 2015 – Present

• Building a platform to develop and benchmark digital ads

- Recently learns about blockchain and focused on NFT as a proof of authenticity
- Developing a minimalist Golang toolkit, especially a http.Handler muxer using *http.Request as its matcher <u>github.com/hokonco/kitgo</u>
- Building modular web component using github.com/WebReflection/lighterhtml
- Creating a reactive data store with additional event target to trigger, the data store itself is embeddable in the component
- 2 way cryptography on server and client, using NaCl and AES GCM with SHA 256
- Sign & verify using NaCl public key exchange to ensure integrity of information
- Developing ReactJS apps as an interface of storage and warehouse systems.
- Using serverless endpoint <u>webtask.io</u>, user identity platform <u>auth0.com</u>, webhook and Amazon Web Services.

Freelance Jan 2015 – Sep 2015

- Provide business and technical analysis for an easier management system for housing companies and inventory stock tracking system.
- Self-learning MongoDB + Express + AngularJS + Node.JS and also Ruby on Rails while tested on job-hunting and personal projects.
- Projects
 - o Interviewed and given a task to develop GPS location based car rental tracker system by Smove Singapore (MongoDB, Express, AngularJS, Node.JS)
 - o Interviewed and given a task to develop mentorship education system with scraper and data visualization by Cialfo Singapore (Ruby on Rails, AngularJS)

Final Project and Thesis

Mar 2013 - Sep 2013

- Developed a centralized home automation system using Python and PHP with data logging feature and remote control via web.
- Plan and design database, login flow, network, concurrent connection and daemon service for Internet of Things.
- Projects
 - Developed Raspberry Pi based home automation system with centralized control (PHP, Python, MySQL, AJAX)

Dual Internship

Sep 2012 – Jan 2013

- Provide business and technical analysis for an easier hotel booking system with thousands of customers and over USD10K transactions per day.
- Convert email and text message booking system to new integration and reporting system for management purposes.
- Projects
 - Analyze, design, testing, and implementation of the booking system for 2 of the best hotels in Kuta, Bali Padma Resort Bali and Discovery Kartika Plaza Hotel. Build integration with legacy email and text message booking system for customer and report for management (PHP, Bootstrap, MySQL, AJAX)

Education

BS in Computer Science, STTS – $\underline{stts.edu}$

Nov 2013

Languages

Native: Indonesian (Bahasa Indonesia)

Fluent: English

Interest: Chinese (漢語), Japanese (日本語)